S. Guy Endore papers, 1925-1970
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts by Guy Endore
  - King of Paris. New York: Simon & Schuster., 1966 (Boxes 2-8, 20, 44, 52-54, 67)
    - Screenplay by Guy Endore for Seven Arts Productions. Los Angeles., undated; (321 leaves, mimeographed. In a grey manila folder) (Boxes 20, 52-53)
      - Draft of screenplay(?). n.p., undated; (75 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 53)
      - Typescript with holograph corrections., undated; (pp.2-113) (Box 53)
    - Introduction. n.p., undated; (26pp. Typescript) (Box 53)
    - Typescript carbon with holograph corrections., undated; (39pp.) (Box 53)
      With photograph of J.L. Gerome's, Duel after the masquerade, with note from James Pere on the verso (8 × 10 in. Black and White photograph).
    - Correspondence re King of Paris. v.p., 1961-1968; (13 leaves, typescript, typescript carbon, and reproduction of typescript) (Box 53)
      Drafts and copies of Endore's letters to Stanley Rubin, Ray Stark, Jay Livingston, and Ray Evans. With 3 replies.
    - Synopsis for publicity campaign[?]. n.p., undated; (3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 53)
    - King of Paris. A final word. n.p., undated; (6 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 53)
      With 2 other copies (Typescript and typescript carbon).
    - Musical ideas for King of Paris. Jay Livingston and Ray Evans. n.p., undated; (3 leaves, typescript) (Box 53)
    - King of Paris. n.p., undated; (59 leaves, typescript, mimeograph, reproduction of typescript and 46pp.) (Box 53)
      Includes partial lyrics for musical production, and draft of staging.
    - Script for demo record of King of Paris. n.p., January 1960(?); (36pp., lacking pp.19-22, mimeograph with holograph notes) (Box 53)
      With postal receipt.
    - Book by Guy Endore. Music and Lyrics by Jay Livingston and Ray Evans. n.p., undated; (125 leaves, mimeograph. With blue cover) (Box 53)
      with list of songs on front flyleaf
    - Outline for musical production. n.p., undated; (52pp., typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 53)
    - Book by Guy Endore. Music and lyrics by Jay Livingston and Ray Evans. n.p., undated; (125 leaves, mimeograph with orange cover) (Box 54)
    - Musical outline for King of Paris. n.p., undated; (3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 54)
    - Musical numbers for King of Paris. n.p., 1968; (50 leaves, holograph, typescript, typescript carbon, and reproduction of typescript) (Box 54)
      Includes letter from Endore to Ray Evans and Jay Livingston, August 4, 1968.
    - Musical scenario for King of Paris. n.p., undated; (19 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 54)
    - Lyrics for King of Paris. n.p., undated; (12 items, typescript) (Box 54)
    - Notes for staging and lyrics. n.p., undated; (14 leaves Holograph, typescript) (Box 54)
    - Talks--statements re King of Paris. v.p., 1956-1960; (44 items) (Box 54)
      Correspondence regarding speaking engagements following publication of King of Paris in 1956.
    - Ephemera., (82 items) (Box 67)
    - Ephemera., (190 items, removed from scrapbook) (Box 67)
  - Life of Sigmund Freud. n.p., 1939-1940 (Boxes 41, 44)
    - Typescript, typescript carbon, holograph., undated; (18 leaves) (Box 41)
    - Freud. A suggestion by Guy Endore. n.p., October 4, 1939; (5 leaves, typescript carbon; 10 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections; 2 leaves, typescript) (Box 41)
      With Sigmund Freud, and draft (second version) of letter to Anna Freud.
      See also: The life of Sigmund Freud, box 44.
    - Partial story outline, and miscellaneous pages. n.p., 1940; (13pp., typescript with holograph notes) (Box 44)
      See also: (Freud), box 41.
  - “... like the covers of an old book.” n.p., undated; (71pp., typescript carbon) (Box 44)
    - “... like the covers of an old book.” Second draft. n.p., undated; (71pp., typescript carbon) (Box 44)
      For the Ben Casey television series.
    - Copy 3. n.p., undated; (63pp., typescript carbon) (Box 44)
      With additional dialogue (3 leaves, holograph)
  - The Little River that Went Dry. n.p., undated; (3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 44)
  - The Long Revenge. n.p., undated (Box 44)
    - Outline. n.p., undated; (3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 44)
    - Typescript carbon. n.p., undated; (34 leaves) (Box 44)
  - Lou Carlino. n.p., undated; (1 leaf. Typescript) (Box 44)
  - Love. n.p., undated (Box 44)
    - Typescript carbon., (20pp., with grey cover) (Box 44)
    - Typescript carbon., (6 leaves) (Box 44)
  - Love is Blind. Far Rockaway, Long Island., July 4, 1932; (13pp., typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 44)
    Also known as: See How They Run.
  - Luck Versus Work. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 44)
    With 1 leaf holograph notes.
  - Man's Mind. n.p., undated; (1 leaf, typescript carbon) (Box 45)
  - Mark the Twain. n.p., undated; (10 leaves, holograph and typescript) (Box 45)
    Includes notes, chronology.
  - Max Linder. n.p., undated; (11 leaves, holograph) (Box 45)
    Chronology and outline.
  - A Modern Solomon. New York., undated; (30pp. Typescript) (Box 45)
  - Money Money. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 45)
  - The Montenegro Case: A Study of the Coroner's Inquest. n.p., 1946 and undated (Boxes 1, 45)
    - Mimeographed copy., (In blue paper cover) (Box 1)
      Also, a report on the Montenegro shooting prepared by the Civil Rights Congress (mimeographed), a letter, and petition issued by the Civil Rights Congress.
    - Typescript carbon., undated; (37pp. with blue cover) (Box 45)
    - Typescript carbon and holograph., undated; (37pp.) (Box 45)
      With 1 leaf manuscript insertion for p.32.
  - Morocco: Booming by Day. Bombing by Night. n.p., undated (Box 45)
    - Typescript carbon with holograph corrections., (8 leaves) (Box 45)
    - Typescript carbon., (6 leaves) (Box 45)
  - My Father My Foe., March 9, 1955; (Typescript with holograph corrections, irregular pagination. 1 reel, positive) (Box 11)
    See also, Box 97
  - Myths, Borgeois and Marxist, and the Answer to Them. n.p., undated; (9 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 45)
  - Nachtstueck. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 45)
  - The Naked Heart. n.p., undated (Box 45)
    - Introductory note by the editor; editor's prologue; introductory word by the editor., (4 leaves, typescript) (Box 45)
    - Typescript carbon., (2 leaves) (Box 45)
      Written for Millen Brand, Crown Books.
  - Negro Question in America. n.p., undated; (2 leaves, typescript) (Box 45)
  - Night-Dreaming. n.p., 1940; (13pp.) (Box 45)
    Published in The Clipper, August 1940.
  - Old Vienna. n.p., undated; (6pp., typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - On writing a book about Tom Mooney. Los Angeles and n.p., undated (Box 46)
    - Notes., (44 leaves, holograph) (Box 46)
      With letter and sketch from V.K. regarding a room for rent in Berkeley.
    - Notes., (25 leaves, typescript, and typescript carbon with holograph corrections) (Box 46)
    - Typescript., (20pp.) (Box 46)
      With typescript draft (8 leaves)
    - Typescript carbon with holograph notes. Los Angeles., (20pp.) (Box 46)
    - Typescript carbon., (20pp.) (Box 46)
  - Overpopulation. Los Angeles and n.p., 1969 and undated (Box 46)
    - Notes. n.p., (7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 46)
    - Notes. Los Angeles., 1969; (7 leaves, reproduction of typescript) (Box 46)
      With photocopy of letter to the Los Angeles Times, April 28, 1969.
  - Our Children Shall Fly. n.p., undated; (6 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 46)
    With a typescript copy and 2 photocopies.
  - Overnight. A treatment by Guy Endore from the novel by Joe Lederer. Los Angeles., undated; (14pp., typescript carbon with grey cover, red label) (Box 46)
    Handled by Sam Jaffe, Incorporated.
  - Paderewski. A film treatment of his life. n.p., 1966 and undated (Box 55)
    - Narrative for film treatment. n.p., undated; (26pp. Reproduction of typescript) (Box 55)
    - Draft letters to Sidney Harmon re Paderewski., May 1966; (15 leaves, typescript, reproduction of typescript) (Box 55)
      Includes letters, copies, draft pages
    - Typescript., (47pp.) (Box 55)
      Also, reproduction of typescript with holograph corrections.
    - Notes on Paderewski. n.p., January-May 1966; (13 items, typescript and typescript carbon) (Box 55)
      Memos with comments by Sidney Harmon.
    - Correspondence re Paderewski. v.p., 1966; (2 items: typescript, and reproduction of typescript) (Box 55)
      Letter from George Willner to Endore (May 30, 1966) lacks enclosures mentioned.
    - Notes on Paderewski. n.p., undated; (14 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 55)
    - Typescript carbon., undated; (87pp.) (Box 55)
    - Reproduction of typescript., undated; (26pp.) (Box 55)
    - Reproduction of typescript., undated; (26pp.) (Box 55)
    - Typescript carbon., undated; (5 leaves) (Box 55)
  - Palimpsest. New York., undated; (5 leaves, typescript) (Box 46)
  - Notes on Paracelsus. Los Angeles., 1944; (6 leaves, typescript) (Box 46)
    With another copy (Typescript carbon), and 3 leaves with extra copies of pp.2-3.
    Also with carbon copy of letter to Virginia Viertel, August 17, 1944.
  - Peace plan. n.p., undated; (5 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - Pirate Story. Screen treatment(?). n.p., undated; (pp.2-60. Typescript carbon. With partial blue cover) (Box 46)
  - Poetry by Guy Endore. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript) (Box 46)
    Each signed on the verso, S.G. Endore.
  - Population Explosion. n.p., undated (Boxes 55-56)
    Also Known as A Thousand Years From Now.
    - Drafts of opening pages, using both titles., (17 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 55)
    - Typescript., (27 leaves, with grey cover) (Box 55)
      With copy 6 (in dark green cover).
    - Mimeograph., (27 leaves, with red cover) (Box 55)
      Hugh King (a pseudonym for Guy Endore) has been crossed out on the title page, and Guy Endore has signed it.
    - Mimeograph., (78pp., with beige cover) (Box 55)
    - Mimeograph (3 copies)., (78pp., with blue covers) (Box 55)
    - Mimeograph (4 copies)., (78pp., with blue covers) (Box 56)
  - Les Principes de la Philosophie by Rene Descarte. Translated toward a Ph.D. at Columbia University., 1926-1927; (Typescript with holograph foreword) (Box 2)
  - Pushkin (Boxes 11, 46)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., (1 reel, negative microfilm) (Box 11)
    - Suggestions for revision of treatment. n.p., undated; (11 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - Recently our cat came running... n.p., 1965 (Box 94)
    - Draft, illustrated., 1965; (5-7, (1)p. illustrated. 33 × 36 cm) (Box 94)
    - Draft., (4pp.) (Box 94)
  - The Rising Storm. n.p., undated (Box 46)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., (15pp.) (Box 46)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., (23pp.) (Box 46)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., (30pp.) (Box 46)
  - The Rosenbergs. n.p., undated; (20 leaves, typescript with holograph notes) (Box 46)
    Notes, research material, clippings.
  - Rothschild. n.p., undated; (8 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 46)
    With 5 leaves holograph manuscript.
  - Rumba. n.p., May 25, 1934; (43pp., typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - The Saga of Synanon. Los Angeles., 1967 (Boxes 30, 32, 48, 60-63, 68, 91)
    - Typescript with copious holograph additions and corrections., 1967; (500 leaves) (Box 30)
    - Mimeographed copy., 1967; (461 leaves) (Box 30)
    - Mimeographed copy. Los Angeles., 1967; (461 leaves) (Box 30)
    - Printer's copy., 1967; (494 leaves, typescript) (Box 32)
    - Galleys. New York: Doubleday., 1968 (Box 32)
    - Page proofs. New York: Doubleday., 1968 (Box 32)
    - Dederich, Betty. The Hatchery (Poem). n.p., undated; (2 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 48)
      Dederich was the wife of Synanon founder, Charles Dederich.
    - Notes on Synanon. n.p., undated; (100 leaves Holograph) (Box 60)
    - Ephemera re Synanon., 1964-1971; (4 items) (Box 60)
    - Thickened Light. n.p., undated; (25 leaves, typescript, holograph) (Box 60)
      Endore's notes re Charles Dederich and Synanon.
    - Untitled story. n.p., undated; (10pp. Typescript with summary, 2pp.) (Box 60)
      Characters are based on Synanon members
    - Notes. Los Angeles., 1967; (60 leaves Holograph. In green spiral notebook) (Box 60)
    - One thousand words about Synanon. n.p., undated; (3pp. Typescript) (Box 60)
    - Correspondence. v.p., 1966-1970; (12 items) (Box 60)
      Primarily correspondence with Reid Kimball. Includes memo from Charles Dederich to Synanon members.
    - Synanon is the People Business. Los Angeles., 1967; (5 leaves, typescript, holograph) (Box 60)
      Mockup of Synanon brochure with note from Mike Kaiser.
    - Photograph of Bill Crawford (Signed). n.p., undated; (1 item. 8 × 10 black/white glossy print) (Box 60)
    - Mimeograph. n.p., undated; (461pp.) (Box 60)
    - Mimeograph with index. n.p., undated; (461pp.) (Box 61)
    - Mimeograph. n.p., undated; (461pp., in original box) (Box 61)
      Endore indicates this is original version.
      Noted on box: Property of Charles Dederich
    - Mimeograph. n.p., undated; (461pp.) (Box 62)
    - Holograph, typescript, and reproduction of typescript. n.p., undated; (500 leaves) (Box 62)
      Corrected and edited manuscript, heavily annotated, with a number of additional pages and changes laid in
    - Portions of text. n.p., undated; (300 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections, and reproduction of typescript) (Box 63)
    - Portions of text. n.p., undated; (300 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections, reproduction of typescript) (Box 63)
    - Ephemera., (8 items) (Box 68)
    - 2 vols. n.p., undated; (250pp. each, typescript carbon) (Box 91)
      (Addition, September 1987)
    - Manuscript pages. n.p., undated; (150 leaves. Mimeo) (Box 91)
    - Typescript. n.p., undated; (pp.22-175) (Box 91)
  - Satan's saint; a novel about the Marquis de Sade. Los Angeles., 1961-1965 (Boxes 23, 24, 26, 27, 40, 56-59, 68, 92)
    Variant titles: Marquis de Sade. A Novel, A Saint for Sinners: a Novel about the Marquis de Sade. A Novel
    Published, New York: Crown Publishers, [1965]
    - Marquis de Sade.. Los Angeles., 1963; (453 leaves, mimeographed. no.9 of 10 numbered copies) (Box 23)
    - A Saint for Sinners: a Novel about the Marquis de Sade. A Novel. Los Angeles., 1963; (200 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections and additions) (Box 23)
      Original manuscript.
    - Worksheets. Los Angeles., 1963; (600 leaves, typescript with copious holograph corrections and revisions) (Box 24)
    - Final version published by Crown Publishers in 1965. Los Angeles., 1964; (450 leaves, typescript with copious holograph corrections and additions) (Box 26)
    - Advertisement for Satan's Saint as it appeared in the New York Times Book Review., April 11, 1965; (1 leaf, photostatic copy) (Box 26)
    - Mimeographed (no.2 of 10 numbered copies). Los Angeles., 1963; (453 leaves) (Box 27)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections. Los Angeles., 1965; (426 leaves) (Box 27)
    - Work sheets mostly for Satan's Saint. Los Angeles., 1965; (Typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 28)
    - Concerning the Marquis de Sade. A Novel. Los Angeles., undated; (26pp., mimeograph) (Box 40)
    - Research material., (3 items) (Box 56)
      Contents: bibliography, issue of Instead (November 1948), and translation of de Sade's letter to Napoleon.
    - Legal on Sade and Simon & Schuster. v.p., 1961-1963; (19 items) (Box 56)
      Correspondence with publishers.
    - Sade publishing. v.p., 1961-1962; (25 items) (Box 56)
      Includes correspondence with Simon & Schuster, reference correspondence, and related material.
    - Sade publishing. v.p., 1961-1964; (75 items) (Box 56)
      Includes correspondence, drafts of letters, and notes.
    - Tamarind Lithography Workshop. Los Angeles., 1965; (2 items) (Box 56)
      An advertisement regarding the deluxe edition of Satan's Saint with lithographs by Robert Hansen and 1 letter (November 4, 1964).
    - Lecture. Los Angeles., 1962; (14pp., typescript carbon with holograph corrections) (Box 56)
      Given before the graduating class of Library Science, UCLA (May 25, 1962) re the publishing difficulties of Satan's Saint.
    - Satan's Saint/Dear Paula. n.p., undated; (24pp. Typescript. With another copy) (Box 56)
    - Satan's Saint. n.p., 1962-1965 (Boxes 56-57, 59)
      - Notes and draft pages. n.p., undated; (150 leaves, typescript, holograph) (Box 56)
      - Portions of manuscript. n.p., undated; (100 leaves, typescript, typescript carbon, and reproduction of typescript) (Box 56)
      - Typescript carbon., 1962; (151pp.) (Box 57)
      - Portions of text revised by Guy Endore. n.p., undated; (200 leaves, typescript) (Box 57)
      - Typescript and typescript carbon with some corrections. n.p., undated; (75 leaves) (Box 57)
      - Notes regarding manuscript corrections. n.p., undated; (11 items. Typescript) (Box 57)
      - Screen treatment. n.p., undated; (3 leaves, typescript) (Box 59)
      - Setting copy. London., 1965; (305pp.) (Box 59)
        Copy of American edition (Crown, 1965) edited for the London edition published by W.H. Allen.
    - Marquis de Sade. A Novel., 1962-1967 (Boxes 57-59)
      - vol.2. n.p., undated; (pp.152-300, typescript carbon) (Box 57)
      - vol.3. n.p., undated; (pp.301-420, typescript carbon) (Box 57)
        With author's note following p.420.
      - Mimeograph (copy 1 of 10). n.p., undated; (453pp., with red cover) (Box 57)
      - Mimeograph (copy 8 of 10). n.p., undated; (453pp., with red cover) (Box 58)
      - Mimeograph (copy 10 of 10) with introductory note. n.p., undated; (453pp.) (Box 58)
        With 4 leaves, laid in
      - Extra circulating copy. n.p., undated; (453pp., mimeograph) (Box 59)
        With text for title page of deluxe edition laid in.
      - Lecture letters. v.p., 1962-1967; (100 items) (Box 59)
        Letters regarding Satan's Saint, related lecture, and responses.
    - Ephemera., (76 items) (Box 68)
    - Marquis de Sade. A Novel (Copy 4 of 10). n.p., undated; (453pp., mimeograph) (Box 92)
      Inscribed on title page to Ben & Mary Clarke.
  - Sea-change. n.p., undated; (24pp., typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - E. Rodney V.G. (pseudonym) The Secret of Good Health. n.p., undated; (8 leaves. Photocopy) (Box 27)
  - The Shoulders of a Giant. Los Angeles., February 18, 1962 (Box 46)
    - Typescript carbon with holograph corrections., (1 leaf) (Box 46)
    - Mimeograph., (3 leaves) (Box 46)
  - Siege of Alcazar. n.p., November 28, 1936; (55pp., typescript carbon with brown cover) (Box 46)
  - Silent Melody. n.p., undated; (48pp., typescript carbon with orange cover) (Box 46)
  - S.J.V. New York., 1927; (112 leaves, typescript) (Box 29)
  - The Sleepy Lagoon Mystery (with llustrations by Giacomo Patri). Los Angeles: Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee., 1944 (Boxes 17, 83)
    - The Sleepy Lagoon mystery, 1944 June; Endore, S. Guy, 1901-1970; Patri, Giacomo, b. 1898, 1898-; Bound in wrappers.; (48pp.) (Box 17)
      Endore presents the facts of the Sleepy Lagoon case. Introduction written by Carey McWilliams, Chairman, Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee.
    - Letters re Sleepy Lagoon Mystery. Los Angeles: Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee., 1944; (9 items) (Box 83, Folder 2)
      From Casselberry, Horace (undated). Copy of a letter addressed to William Randolph Hearst (1 item)
      From Crown Publishers. New York (July 5, 1944). Signed by Edmund Fuller (1 item).
      From Council for Civic Unity. Los Angeles (June 29, 1944) (1 item).
      From Kurnitz, Harry (June 29, 1944) (1 item).
      From Little, Brown & Company, New York (July 14, 1944) (1 item).
      From McWilliams, Carey (June 29, 1944) (1 item).
      From New Masses (undated). Copy of unsigned letter to the editor (1 item).
      From New York Times Book Review. New York (July 21, 1944). Signed by J. Donald Adams. With note from Guy Endore's aunt, Eva Robin, on the verso (1 item).
      From Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation Beverly Hills (July 24, 1944). Signed by Jo Swerling (1 item).
    - Press release re Sleepy Lagoon Mystery. Los Angeles., 1944; (1p. Mimeograph) (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Isserman's comments on Endore's manuscript for The Sleepy Lagoon Mystery., (5pp.) (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Speak to the Earth. The story of Luther Burbank. n.p., undated; (35pp., mimeograph typescript, with black cover) (Box 46)
    With another copy (black cover).
  - A story. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 46)
  - Suez. n.p., November 5, 1951; (7pp., typescript carbon with blue cover) (Box 46)
  - Sunday-Child. New York., undated; (8pp., typescript carbon) (Box 47)
    Signed S. Guy Endore on p.8.
  - The Superiority Complex. n.p., undated; (10 leaves Holograph) (Box 47)
  - The Sword of God. New York: Farrar & Rinehard., 1931; (Typescript carbon, in pale blue paper cover) (Box 1)
  - The Syndicate. n.p., undated (Box 47)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., (2 leaves) (Box 47)
      With another version (2 leaves).
    - Screenplay., (116pp., typescript carbon) (Box 47)
    - Revised screenplay., (127pp., typescript carbon with grey cover) (Box 47)
    - Revised screenplay., (127pp., typescript carbon with tan cover) (Box 47)
  - Tell me, Tell me by Benjamin Martin. n.p., undated; (3 vol., typescript carbon) (Box 92)
    Addition, September 1987
    - vol.1, pp.1-117 (Box 92)
    - vol.2, pp.118-236 (Box 92)
    - vol.3, pp.237-459 (Box 93)
  - Therefore Socrates is mortal. New York., undated; (6pp., typescript carbon) (Box 47)
  - Tragic fate of a gourmet. The fate of Cornelius Redfield. Long Island., undated (Box 47)
    Also known as: Tragic fate of a gourmet.
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., undated; (7pp.) (Box 47)
    - Holograph., (9 leaves) (Box 47)
      There are 2 copies of pp.6 and 7.
  - Two sermons on books. Los Angeles., October 1, 1969; (13pp., mimeograph) (Box 47)
    Printed for the first Unitarian Church of Los Angeles.
  - Tycoon. n.p., undated; (43pp., typescript carbon with grey cover) (Box 47)
  - Uncle Boaz. A play by Guy Endore. n.p., undated; (72 leaves, typescript carbon. With grey cover) (Box 47)
  - Uncle Jacob. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript) (Box 47)
    Also, another version with holograph corrections (4 leaves, typescript).
  - [Various Endore titles]., (6 reels negative microfilm) (Box 97)
    False Witness
    Battle of the Philosophers
    A Tale of the Christ
    Detour Through Devon
    Pushkin
    My Father My Foe
  - Voltaire! Voltaire!. Los Angeles., 1960 (Boxes 7, 19, 47, 68)
    [Published, New York: Simon & Schuster, 1961]
    - Printer's copy. Los Angeles., 1961; (787 leaves, typescript with copious corrections) (Box 7)
    - Typescript., 1960; (564 leaves with holograph corrections in pencil and red ink) (Box 19)
    - Galley proofs., (192 sheets) (Box 19)
    - Uncorrected and unpublished manuscript. Crane's Duplicating Service. Barnstable, Massachusetts., 1960; (2 vol., photostatic reproduction) (Box 19)
    - Galley proofs (Duplicate proof). H. Wolff Book Manufacturing Company., March 13, 1961; (252 sheets) (Box 19)
    - Notes re Voltaire. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript, holograph) (Box 47)
    - Ephemera., (133 items) (Box 68)
  - The Walburgur Case. n.p., undated (Boxes 1, 47)
    - Typescript carbon., (In pale blue paper cover) (Box 1)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections., undated; (26 leaves) (Box 47)
  - A Walk in Alabama. Los Angeles and n.p., April 6, 1965 and undated (Box 47)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections. n.p., undated (Box 47)